http://www.newcastle.anglican.org/privacy/

Church Schools
HomeMission & MinistryAbout UsAuthorised MinistriesOur FaithCollecting Statistics for MissionAdministration of Parish FinanceParish ShareContinuing Ministerial DevelopmentCMD ResourcesCMD eventsCounselling ProvisionCounselling ResourcesCounselling BlogDiocesan Advisory Committee for the Care of Churches (DAC)Public Notices for Major WorksArchaeological AssessmentsChancel Repair Liability and RegistrationDisability MattersDiscipleshipEcumenismEnvironmentGenerous GivingForms of generosityVolunteering HubFundraisingSustaining donations (COVID-19) Virtual fundraisingGenerous Giving NewsletterGiving reviewsContactless givingeasyfundraisingLegacy givingThe Generous Giving ChallengeParish Giving SchemeDigital giving (COVID-19) Examples of digital givingPreaching and teachingVolunteering opportunities (COVID-19)Top tips for good stewardshipMeet the teamEvangelismEvangelism Task GroupPilgrim CourseEvangelism ResourcesBible Study ReviewEvangelism TrainingMission Action Plan 2016-2019'Way Ahead' bookletMission WeekendsEvangelism PlanningInterfaithMinistry MattersRetired ClergyFees for retired clergyNewcastle Diocesan Sons of the Clergy SocietyRetired clergy support teamEvents for retired clergyThe Rural StrandRural Churches for EveryoneContextual Practice WorkshopsWorkshop ReportsRural ResourcesInspired North EastRural AffairsPartner OrganisationsJoint Education TeamNewcastle upon Tyne Church of England Institute TrustMothers' UnionSetting God's People Free (SGPF)Directory of useful resourcesOther useful resourcesUnderstanding the BibleIncreasing confidenceWorking togetherSGPF ResourcesWorship and MusicVocationsOrdinands' VideosTraining and Reference MaterialsInitial Ministerial Education 4-7 / IME Phase TwoInitial Ministerial Education 1-3 / IME Phase OneDiocesan Handbooks for Clergy and ParishesLindisfarne College of TheologyMajor Incident PolicyDiscipleshipDiscipleship in Daily LifeFollow Me on MondayA Compelling Vision for Discipleship in Daily LifePermission to OfficiateOrdinations 2020VacanciesPeople & PlacesPeople SearchBishop's StaffDean of NewcastleArchdeaconsArchdeacons' briefingsOur BishopsBishop ChristinePrivacy PolicyChaplainsChaplains in Higher EducationChaplains in Health Services and HospitalsOur DioceseFind a personDiocesan SynodDiocesan Synod MembersDiocesan Synod ArchiveDeanery OfficersChurchwardensGeneral SynodLife EventsWeddingsFuneralsBaptismsConfirmationsSafeguardingParish Safeguarding HandbookReporting Abuse and Finding SupportPast Cases Review 2Safeguarding Learning Events Programme 2020Safer Recruitment for volunteers, paid posts and DBSMeet the Safeguarding TeamParish AuditNational and Diocesan Policy and Practice GuidanceGovernanceWebsites and social mediaAdditional ResourcesRecent ArticlesCoronavirusCreative church when worship isn't possibleResources for families and childrenLive streamingCoronavirus - Safeguarding Coronavirus weekly round-up
Home > People & Places
> Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
People & PlacesPeople SearchBishop's StaffPrivacy PolicyChaplainsOur DioceseFind a personDiocesan SynodDeanery OfficersChurchwardensGeneral Synod
The Newcastle Diocesan Board of Finance is committed to protecting your personal data that we hold. We want you to know that you can trust us to respect your privacy and keep your personal information safe.On 25th May 2018 new legislation came into force called the General Data Protection Regulation, which is usually referred to as GDPR. This new legislation provides you with additional safeguards for how your personal data is used and stored. It allows you to have more control over what happens to your information, for example, if you no longer wish to receive our newsletter we will stop sending this when you ask us to cease.We have developed a number of privacy notices which are included on this page. These give you an overview of the information we collect; how we use it; who we share it with; and how we protect your data. In the interests of transparency we have also included our Data Protection Policy. Data Protection PolicyData Privacy NoticeJob Applicant Privacy NoticeOffice Holder and Employee Privacy NoticeCanon Shane WaddleData Compliance Officer for the Newcastle Diocesan Board of FinanceThe Church of England Diocese of Newcastle website (newcastle.anglican.org)Glossary of termsWe, we, us, Newcastle Diocese, Diocese of Newcastle: Newcastle Diocesan Board of Finance - A company limited by guarantee Reg. No. 650977 / Charity No. 247233DisclaimerThis policy was last updated on the: 18th January 2019Your regular review of these terms is assumed with your continued use of the website.We do not provide any warranty or guarantee as to the accuracy, timeliness, performance, completeness or sustainability of the information and materials found and offered on this website for any particular purpose.Despite our best efforts this website in whole may contain errors, we do not accept liability for loss or damage caused by inaccurate information.Use of any information or materials on this website is entirely at your own risk, for which we shall not be liable. It shall be your own responsibility to ensure that any products/services or information available including without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any loss or damage whatsoever arising from the loss of data or profits arising out of, or in connection with the use of this website meet you specific requirements; in no event will we be liable for any loss or damage including without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any loss or damage whatsoever arising from the loss of data or profits arising out of, or in connection with the use of this website.We may include links to and from other sites, by following these links you are agreeing to the respective sites own terms and policies; we hold not obligation or further contract once you have left the pages of our site and accept no responsibility or liability for the contents of these sites or their terms.We hold no control over the content of such sites and disclaim any liability in respect of your use of such sites.We do not like spam, and will never knowingly send spam to you.We will never sell, rent or otherwise distribute or make public your personal information without your permissions.AboutThe Diocese of Newcastle are committed to protecting the personal information of our users. This policy answers some important questions about how we collect, use and protect your personal details including: What personally identifiable
information is collected from you through this website (https:// newcastle.anglican.org), how it is used and with whom
it may be shared. What choices are available
to you regarding your data Security procedures we
have in place to protect your personal information information about our
cookies policy.The Newcastle Diocesan data privacy notice covering other interactions with is (i.e. not through this website) is available at the top of this page.How and why we collect informationAs with the vast majority of websites, this website automatically collects information relating to requests sent via your computer/web browser, this information is used for system administration and bug tracking, to detect site misuse and to provide statistical information related to the usage of the website. The information collected will be kept and reviewed periodically.Information is also collected through our online contact forms and email links
we will use your information to reply to your communication but it is never shared with third parties without your consent (except through that of our website development company Developer Society Limited)What we collectWhen using our website we sometimes receive personal information about you. For example, if you fill in a contact form you will tell us who you are and how we can contact you, any comment you might make and any message you leave/submit through contact forms.We will also collect anonymised browsing information, through Google Analytics such as: Page InformationURL
the URL of the page the user is viewingTitle
the title of the page the user is viewing Browser InformationBrowser name
the browser the user is usingViewport or Viewing pane
the size of the browser windowScreen resolution
the resolution of the users screenJava enabled
whether or not the user has Java enabled User InformationLocation
this is derived from the IP address where the hit originated. The IP address itself is anonymized and cannot be seenLanguage
derived from the language settings of the browserDate and time you visit our websiteDevice The type of device your using (Desktop, mobile, tablet), branding model and marketing name of your device (if available) and your service providerSource/Medium - where your came from. The Source is the place you were are before seeing coming to our website, like a search engine or another website. The Medium describes how you arrived at our website.Viewing behaviour
includes information of which pages you visit, which page you viewed beforehand, how long you are on a page, what links you clicked and which page you visited next (or if you left the site)
This information is a gathered statistic and cannot be used to personally identifyNo personally identifiable information is collected about you unless you explicitly submit that information on this website. We are not able to single out any single user of our website using the data we collect.Our Google Analytics data retention period is currently set to 26 months; all new data will reset the retention period of the user identifier with each new event from that user (thus setting the expiration date to current time plus retention period).How we use this informationSummary statistics are extracted from the data collected, some of which may be made publicly available
however these will not include any personal information by which individuals could be identified.If you pass information to us through the website including contact information we may use this to reply to your communication, provide you with services (eg. e-Bulletins), alert you to other relative information, events, news, etc. We will keep your information confidential and generally we will only use your information within the Diocese of NewcastleWe will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.Third PartiesGoogle AnalyticsThis website uses Google Analytics to help analyse how visitors use this site. Google Analytics uses cookies, which are small text files placed on your computer, to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information in an anonymous form.The anonymised information generated by Google Analytics cookies about your use of this website is transmitted directly to Google. This information is processed to compile statistical reports on website activity for this website only. The Diocese of Newcastle use these reports to evaluate aggregate visitor usage so that we can optimise the content, and its marketing, to better meet your needs.For an overview of privacy at Google (www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy)To find out how Google Analytics anonymises IP addresses (https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en)To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout - Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of the Diocese of Newcastle websiteDeveloper Society LimitedWebsite hosting
Account information
Contact formsShare ThisOnline social media sharing serviceCookiesCookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit.To learn more about cookies, you can visit www.aboutcookies.org. You will also find details on how to block and delete cookies from your computer as well as more general information about cookies. For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile phone you will need to refer to your handset manual.You can find out more about cookies and how they work from Directgov (https://www.gov.uk/help/cookies)Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of newcastle.anglican.org websiteThe Cookies We UseSessionid
About this cookie:This is a very generic cookie name that may have different purposes on different sites, but generally it will be some kind of anonymous session identifier.The main purpose of this cookie is: Strictly NecessaryCsrftoken
About this cookie: This cookie is associated with the Django web development platform for Python. It is designed to help protect a site against at particular type of software attack on web forms.The main purpose of this cookie is: Strictly NecessaryThe Developer Society (Dev.ngo)Glitter_sidebar
About this cookie: The main purpose of this cookie is: FunctionalityGoogle AnalyticsThese cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies dont collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous.This data helps us to understand: Which pages people visit on
the site Which internet browsers are
being used What is popular on the site Which interactive tools are
used by visitorsOur Google Analytics data retention period is currently set to 26 months; all new data will reset the retention period of the user identifier with each new event from that user (thus setting the expiration date to current time plus retention period).All data collected is visible only to the communications team and the secretary at Newcastle Diocese and is translated into average stats when sharing with a wider team
this information is never shared with third parties.You can find out more about Googles cookies on their privacy policy: www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy.You can also install the Google Analytics Opt-out tools in your browser: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.js Tracking info
Session timeout
30mins
Campaign timeout
6months_gid
About this cookie: This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics. This appears to be a new cookie and as of Spring 2017 no information is available from Google. It appears to store and update a unique value for each page visited.The main purpose of this cookie is: Performance_gat
About this cookie:This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics, according to documentation it is used to throttle the request rate - limiting the collection of data on high traffic sites. It expires after 10 minutes.The main purpose of this cookie is: Performance_ga
About this cookie:This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics - which is a significant update to Google's more commonly used analytics service. This cookie is used to distinguish unique users by assigning a randomly generated number as a client identifier. It is included in each page request in a site and used to calculate visitor, session and campaign data for the sites analytics reports.The main purpose of this cookie is: Performance__utma
About this cookie:This is one of the four main cookies set by the Google Analytics service which enables website owners to track visitor behaviour and measure site performance. This cookie lasts for 2 years by default and distinguishes between users and sessions. It it used to calculate new and returning visitor statistics. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.The main purpose of this cookie is: PerformanceShare ThisThese cookies are__unam
About this cookie:This cookie is usually associated with the ShareThis social sharing widget placed in a site to enable sharing of content across various social networks. It counts clicks and shares of a page.The main purpose of this cookie is: FunctionalityThe __unam cookie is set as part of the ShareThis service and monitors click-stream activity, e.g. web pages viewed and navigated, and time spent on pages.We are advised that the ShareThis service only personally identifies you if you have separately signed up with ShareThis for an account with them and given them your consent.YouTube & VimeoIf you play an embedded video on our site, there may a cookie set by YouTube or Vimeo containing anonymous, non-personally-identifiable information (unless you are logged in to a google account, if so you can find your privacy settings within your account settings) about the number of playbacks of embedded videos. To find out more please visit YouTubes embedding videos information page. You can find out more on the Google Privacy Policy (Google owns YouTube): www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy and the Vimeo Privacy Policy: http://vimeo.com/privacyCopyright & PhotographyAny resources from the Diocese of Newcastle website are free for reproduction in your Parish newsletter, magazine or website. However, if you produce a newsletter or website which is not directly affiliated with the Diocese (a local digest magazine, for example, or news from another religion/denomination) and you would like to use these resources, please gain permission from our Communications Team.Photographs within this website may not be reproduced for any purpose without prior permission which must be obtained in writing from the Communications Team. If you would like to know more about copyright in images please contact the Communications Team.Who to talk toIf you would like to know more about the Diocese of Newcastle, our website or would like some advice about related information please contact our webmaster.MiscellaneousIt is important for you to appreciate that this website provides extensive links to other independent websites, both within the Church of England and outside. This policy only applies to direct access to the Church of England Diocese of Newcastle website
URLs starting with /We are not responsible for the availability or content (including cookies) of external sites that may be linked to, from the site. If you find a broken link or if you have any questions or concerns about a link, please contact our webmaster: communications@newcastle.anglican.orgWe are committed to protecting your personal data but if for some reason you are not happy with any aspect of how we collect and use your data, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioners Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (ico.org.uk).We would be grateful if you would contact us first if you do have a complaint so that we can try to resolve it for you.To exercise all relevant rights, queries, access or complaints please in the first instance contact the Diocesan Secretary either by email or by post: Diocese of Newcastle, Church House, St Johns Terrace, North Shields, NE29 6HS.To find out more about your personal information and what you can do visit the ICO (Information Commissioners Office) website: ico.org.uk/for-the-public.You can contact the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113, via email or at the Information Commissioners Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire SK9 5AF. Printable Version
Diocese of Newcastle
Church House, St John’s Terrace,
North Shields, NE29 6HS
0191 270 4100
Email the Diocese
This website is powered by Church Edit
